

# **VÍCTOR PÉREZ PIQUERAS**

Software Engineer - Scrum Master - Researcher



+34 601 13 94 14



victorperezpiqueras@gmail.com @victorperezpiqueras in víctor-pérez-piqueras





## **ABOUT ME**

I'm a professional, competent and passionate Software Engineer. I'm experienced in web development, frontend design and UI. I also have knowledge in backend, ReST APIs and database design, which allows me to easily adapt to most job positions, being able to work as a full-stack developer.

I enjoy teamworking and pursuing sinergies to get the best of me and the team. I've developed most of my career in english and, thus, I can effectively communicate with my coworkers whether they speak english or spanish.

I'm devoted to clean code practices, design patterns, refactoring principles and continuous integration/deployment techniques. Solid Agile defender and PSM-II.

HARD SKILLS

Web development A

Cloud architectures

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Full Stack Developer & Scrum Master**

Nov. 2021 - Today

Grupo Vermon S.L.

Development of a system for track and fleet monitoring in the rail transport sector. Project in an international, Scrum-managed team (recently holding Scrum Master role), using current technologies such as Angular for frontend and AWS Cloud services for the infrastructure and backend architecture.

### Researcher

Feb. 2021 - Oct. 2021

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Research support staff in R&D&i project. Design and evaluation of multi-objective optimization algorithms. Technologies: Python, Pandas.

#### Full Stack Developer - Internship

Jul. 2020 - Sep. 2020

Development of a web application for the creation and management of dynamic forms to control incidents in companies. Technologies: Angular, AWS Serverless.



Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Full stack development of a web application for real-time home sensor management and monitoring. Technologies: Angular, Python Flask, SQLite.

### **EDUCATION**

Professional Scrum Master II • Scrum.org

2023

#### PhD In Advanced Computer Technologies

2021 - Today

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Part-time researcher at the Intelligent Systems and Data Mining Laboratory.

### Professional Scrum Master I • Scrum.org

2020



**Masters Degree In Computer Science** 

2020 - 2021



Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Multidisciplinary training and management skills. 5 distinctions with honours.

- TFM: "Scrum management software enhancement for automatic Product Backlog prioritization". Technologies: Angular, NodeJS, MySQL, AWS Serverless. Mark: 10.

### **Bachelor's Bilingual Degree In Computer Science**

2016 - 2020

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Mention in Software Engineering. 4 distinctions with honours.

- TFG: "TheProductOwnerd: Support tool for the Product Owner". Technologies: Angular, NodeJS, MySQL. Mark: 10.

Agile development & Scrum



First Certificate In English (B2) • Cambridge

ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

2018

# Clean Code, CI/CD, Testing (

## **SISTEDES - NTT Data Award for the best Masters Thesis**

2022

National award for the best Masters Thesis on new methodologies and tools for software development.

2021

**Charles Babbage Award for the best Masters Thesis** 

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Award for the best Master's Thesis of a multidisciplinary nature and business transfer in the Masters Degree In Computer Science.

### Best Academic Record of the Masters Degree In Computer Science

2021

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha Average mark of 9,80.

### Pictotrainer - Third Award • Esiiab • Hack For Albacity

2020

Web and mobile application for the training and rehabilitation of people with functional diversity, presented to the HackForAlbacity2020 competition in collaboration with the CRMF-IMSERSO.

# SOFT SKILLS

Self learning

Teamwork

Critical thinking

Creativity

